This matter, listen to Xie Xuan
이 일은 사현의 뜻대로 해
If Shilang's army really wants to retreat
만약 석랑의 부대가 정말 퇴각할 생각이라면
Why go to such lengths
왜 이렇게 애써
To block information
소식을 봉쇄하고
Not even a carrier pigeon can enter
전서구 한 마리도 못 들어오게 막을까
Now we're cornered
지금 우리는 막다른 골목에 다다랐고
And completely blind
한 치 앞도 볼 수가 없어
At this time
사람은 이럴 때
We're most likely to become gamblers
도박꾼이 되기 쉽거든
The more so
한데 이럴 수록
The less we should move
경거망동하면 안 돼
Hurry to repair the walls
서둘러 성벽을 보수해라
Yes
예
Xie Xuan
사현
General Liu
유 장군
Continue adding internal defenses
자네들은 계속해서 성내 배치를 늘리게
Yes
예
No movement in the city yet
성안은 아직도 잠잠하냐
Reporting, General
아룁니다
Not yet
아직은 조용합니다
That coward Prince of Jin
진왕 이놈이
Is as timid as a mouse
겁쟁이인가 보네요
Scared by the general
장군이 두려워서
Won't move a step
꼼짝도 못 하고 있어요
General
장군
Chanyu Ayidai these past days
장군 아의대가 전갈을 보내
Has been sending messages asking
물어보네요
If we don't take Yiyang soon
저희가 익양을 뚫지 못하면
Hurry, hurry, hurry
맨날 재촉이야
Hurry your mother
제기랄
Prince of Jin Sikong Yao
진왕 사공요
I'll remember this
내 너를 꼭 기억하마
Return to camp
군영으로 돌아가자
Tell the other side
저쪽에
To prepare for me
준비하라고 해
Report
아룁니다
No activity found in the south
성남 쪽엔 발견이 없습니다
No activity found in the west
성서 쪽도 없습니다
Could they really have withdrawn?
정말 철수했나
What's going on?
대체 어떻게 된 거지
Report
아룁니다
Urgent report
성서의 급보예요
Urgent report from the west
오노가 서쪽에서
The Wuzhao have broken in from the west
성으로 쳐들어왔답니다
Into the city
쳐들어왔다고
How could they enter the city?
어떻게 입성한 거지
Don't panic yet
조급해하지 마
What's the situation in the west now?
지금 서쪽 상황은 어떠냐
I've been hearing
요 며칠 계속
Sounds these past days
움직임이 있긴 했습니다
I've been
전 요즘
Resting poorly lately
잘 자지도 못합니다
Always hearing
항상
Tapping sounds
뚜뚜 소리가 들리며
Always dreaming
제가 오노의
Of Wuzhao horses trampling me
말발굽에 밟히는 꿈을 꿉니다
I thought it was hallucinations
환각이 나타난 줄 알았는데
Now I know
이제야 알겠어요
The Wuzhao dug tunnels
오노가 땅굴을 팠던 겁니다
Undermining the wall foundations
그렇게 성벽을 무너뜨린 거예요
The Wuzhao elite
오노 정예가 이미
Have already emerged from the tunnels
땅굴을 따라 들어와
Taking the gates
성문을 열었습니다
General Liu is holding with his men
유 장군이 병사들을 이끌고 사수하고 있어요
Report
아룁니다
The Wuzhao army from the north has turned back
북쪽의 오노 대군이 방향을 틀어
Preparing to attack the city
성을 공격하려 합니다
The north
북쪽
Many volunteers at the west gate
서성문에는 의병이 많아서
If they defect
그들이 변절한다면
I'm afraid we can't hold
지키기 어렵습니다
Yes, we can't hold
그래요 지키기 어려워요
This is fighting on two fronts
양쪽으로 싸워야 하잖아
But we have so few men
사람도 얼마 없는데
Right
그러게
How can we defend?
이걸 어떻게 지켜
We simply can't hold
불가능한 일이지
Don't panic
당황하지 마라
Everyone
전원
Reinforce the north
북쪽을 지원하고
The northern front
북쪽 전선은
Will be commanded by General Zhu
주 장군이 맡는다
Bring all available equipment
쓸 수 있는 장비는 모두 챙겨서
Must stop the Wuzhao main force
반드시 오노 주력군을 막아야 해
I accept the order
명 받들겠습니다
You all
다들
Follow me
따라와
Yes
예
Xie Xuan
사현